♪ In the not too
distant future ♪
♪ Next Sunday A.D. ♪
♪ There was a guy named Joel ♪
♪ Not too different
from you or me ♪
♪ He worked at
Gizmonic Institute ♪
♪ Just another face
in a red jumpsuit ♪
♪ He did a good job
cleaning up the place ♪
♪ But his bosses
didn't like him ♪
♪ So they shot him into space ♪
♪ We'll send him cheesy movies ♪
♪ The worst we can
find, la la la ♪
♪ He'll have to sit
and watch them all ♪
♪ And we'll monitor
his mind, la la la ♪
♪ Now keep in mind
Joel can't control ♪
♪ Where the movies
begin or end, la la la ♪
♪ Because he used
those special parts ♪
♪ To make his robot friends ♪
♪ Robot roll call ♪
♪ Cambot, pan left ♪
♪ Gypsy, hi girl ♪
♪ Tom Servo, what a cool guy ♪
♪ Crow, he's a wise cracker ♪
♪ If you're wondering how
he eats and breathes ♪
♪ And other science
facts, la la la, ♪
♪ Then repeat to yourself,
it's just a show ♪
♪ I should really just relax ♪
♪ For Mystery Science
Theater 3000 ♪
(doors whirring and slamming)
- [Ship's Computer] 30
seconds to commercial sign.
- Hey, everybody.
I'm Joel, I'm marooned
in outer space
on the Satellite of Love,
and I'm the subject of a bizarre
movie watching experiment.
Now, I guess,
so are you.
I'm up here with my
two homemade buddies,
Crow and Tom Servo, here, yeah.
And we're working
on Tom Servo now.
I think, uh, trying
to fix him up.
- Hey, watch what
you're doing there.
It's the only torso I have.
- [Ship's Computer]
Commercial sign
in 15 seconds.
- Well,
I think I found
the problem here,
buddy.
- No way.
- Some kind of a computer
virus happening here.
- Oh, grody, it looks
like a magnetic tapeworm.
- [Ship's Computer]
Commercial sign in five, four,
three, two.
Commercial sign, now.
- I got it.
You'll be ship-shape in no time.
We'll be right back.
Don't go away,
you'll be real gone.
("The Love Theme Instrumental")
All right, that
oughta do it, buddy.
Hop down and grab
yourself a lollipop.
- Oh, I feel like a new man.
I don't know what
you did, but my back
hasn't felt this good in months.
I'm cooking with Crisco now.
- Funny, you don't
look any better.
(Tom Servo groans)
- Uh oh, you guys,
look downcast, the big
cheeses are calling.
- Come in Joel the Mole, my
little frosted spongecake.
(snickers)
- Hey, sirs, what are
you wrecking today?
- Oh, nothing, really.
We're just kinda hangin'
out and you know, it's--
- Larry!
- I'm sorry.
- It's magic time.
Make with the invention
exchange, plebe.
- Well, as you know,
even avid smokers
can't stand the smell
of a tar-belching pipe,
and so I invented this,
the never-light pipe.
It's got a sophisticated
sprinkler system built
in with a smoke detector,
so any time somebody
tries to light up--
- Ow, that's my scar.
- See, it puts it out for
you. See, I'll try it on that.
- Ouch.
- Like that, they should
never, ever be able to light up
with this thing.
- No more.
- It's not supposed to work.
- Oh!
- Well, what do you think, sirs?
- I think it's almost as
clever as the Prince Albert
in a can gag.
- (chortling) I love
that gag, it's great.
Better let him out,
he'll suffocate.
(guffawing)
- Now get ready for our part.
Larry?
Larry? Now Lar and I have
discovered that children
adore putting things
in their mouth
and they love puppets.
We've combined the two,
put a little spin on it.
We call it Tongue Puppets.
The show, Larry?
- Hey, everybody,
it's me, Mr. Skanky.
Oh, I love everybody here.
Dr. Laurence Erhardt and
Dr. Clayton Forrester.
(giggles) Bye.
- I think you
might win the award
for the most unsanitary toy.
- Well, thank you.
- Thank you very much, yes.
Well done.
- Well, congratulations.
- Absolutely.
- It's about time.
- [All] Oh, brother.
- Well done, excellent.
- We finally got one.
It's about time.
It's great.
(sniffs)
- Great, uh.
- Oh. (giggles)
- Your film today Joel, is
a little teen exploitation
film called...
Untamed Youth, and
uh well, it stars the
grand dame of pimply
teenage romps,
the queen of adolescent
angst, Mamie Van Hooter.
- Doren,
Doren.
- Doren, Mamie Van Doren.
- It's got hep
cats, cool chicks,
insensitive authority figures,
and a few show-stopping
production numbers.
Enjoy, if you can.
(buzzing)
- Oh, we got movie sign!
Let's go!
(doors whirring and slamming)
Oh boy.
- Those scientists
are just geeks.
- [Joel] At least it's a
Warner Brothers picture.
- [Tom] Sounds like it's
gonna be one of those
teen-sploitation things.
- Hey, I hope it's
a cartoon first.
(1950's rock music)
Oh, a Western.
- Anytown, USA.
- [Joel] It looks like
he's playing football
against Claude Rains University.
- [Tom] How much you wanna
bet the word "Daddy-O"
is in the film a million times?
- Hey, after him.
He's hiding behind
those credits.
- [Joel] I think hiding
behind the police
would be easier if this
was before Harvest time.
At least you'd have
some corn, you know.
- I think there's gonna
be a lot of corn in this.
- [Tom] This is like
the Stephen King book,
Children of the Dirt.
- Hey hide, quick.
Hide in plain sight.
- He's roadkill,
look at that.
- [Joel] Don't ever play
Chicken with two cop cars.
You can't win.
- [Tom] Thought you could
hide behind the credits, huh?
Works every time.
- So he stole an onion,
what are you gonna do?
(water splashing)
- [Joel] Is that
the primordial soup?
- Hey, there's a
girl in my soup.
(chuckles)
- [Tom] Don't worry.
She won't eat much.
(laughs)
- [Mitch] Okay, crawl out!
- Well you go away first!
- Oh, that'd be a
neglect of duty.
- Well at least turn around!
- At least they're not
un-bathed youth.
- [Jane] You're not much of
a gentleman.
- It's the Maytag repair man.
He does look lonely.
- I never was.
Now get out!
- [Jack] Hiya, Mitch!
- Oh, hi Landis.
- [Jack] Whatcha doin', fishing?
- No, just sexually
harassing a few teens.
- [Joel] They're swimming
with their high heels on.
- No, no, you stick to
your cotton pickin'.
- [Tom] My cotton pickin' what?
- Nice tag.
(slow 1950's music)
Oh, good I thought
they were gonna put
their luggage on.
- Huh?
What?
- [Joel] So, I understand
you two are untamed.
- How old are you two?
- 22.
- 36.
- 21.
- It's my locker code.
- You don't look no
21 to me.
Where do you live?
- Du Qouin.
- Du-what?
- Du Quoin, Illinois.
- The biggest county
fair in the country.
Sulky races and everything.
- That's where we got our start.
- Entertaining.
- Home of the Fighting
Ducks and the glass bottom
boats.
- Strip tease?
- No, thank you.
- Songs, dances,
skits, any--
- Don't bother briefing him.
- Where were you going?
- To LA.
Whatchu mean, were?
- Just that.
Pick up the stuff.
- You,
you mean you'd take us in
just for swimming around
in that pond?
- We were so hot and
we walked for miles.
No one would pick us up.
- She's still hot.
- Hitchhiking's also
against the county code.
Now pick up that
stuff and let's go.
(jazz music)
- [Joel] What a grouch.
There's no room for our stuff,
the backseat's filled
with a jazz combo.
- No, no, no,
baggage in the back.
You in front.
- Now you drive it into town
and I'll meet you there.
- [Joel] Quit playing that sax.
- [Tom] Meanwhile,
at Mount Vernon.
- Hitchhiking may not seem
a serious offense to you,
but there have been two
murders involving hitchhiking
in the last seven months.
- And I committed both of them.
- In one case, a
hitchhiker killed a man
for his car and money.
- Just for snoring too loud.
- And the other
hitchhiking girl was
assaulted and murdered.
- [Joel] Her name was Peanut.
- You are vagrants.
Without visible
means of support,
hitchhiking about
- Oh, I wouldn't say that.
- the country.
You have plead guilty.
I now sentence you...
- [Joel] To death?
- [Judge Steele] Jane Lowe,
and you Penny Lowe to
30 days confinement.
- [Tom] Huh?
- Now that may
seem harsh to you.
- [Tom] 'Cause it is.
- But I'm going to
give you a choice.
You may serve your sentence
in the county jail.
Or you may serve it as
agricultural workers on a ranch.
- Green Acres?
- There you will
be housed and fed.
- Jail please, jail!
- You will do
healthy, outdoor work
for which you will be paid.
- They look healthy enough.
- And you will regain
your self-respect.
- Uh, your zipper's--
- We never lost it,
your Honor.
- [Tom] What about this movie?
Really stoic judge.
- Make a choice, girls.
- [Joel] They call
her Stone Face.
- Agricultural work.
- We'll take the healthy,
outdoor work, ma'am.
- So decreed.
- Like I care.
- Jim,
Mitch.
Oh, Bob!
What a wonderful surprise!
- Not very judge-like.
- Oh, you were discharged.
So good to see you!
I've got a thousand
things to tell you.
Oh, excuse me a minute.
(giggles)
Court's adjourned
until tomorrow morning.
(gavel bangs)
- [Joel] Then there's gonna be
a big party.
- My son just got out
of the Navy!
(fake chuckle)
- Big deal.
- With her for a mom, that
guy's got a life sentence.
(fake laugh)
- Alright, come on.
Right out the door.
Step right out.
- Kooky teeners.
- [Mitch] Step there,
come on, keep moving.
(dramatic music)
(doo-wop music)
- Any Really Groovy City, USA.
- [Tom] Looks like
Tom Waits' hometown.
- Tire farmin'.
It's hard, but it's worth it.
- [Joel] Somewhere out there
is the Ark of the Covenant.
- In a radio.
- [Tom] Oh I hope it's
not the von Tropp family.
I hate them.
- Hey, it's the Body
Snatcher pod wagon.
- [Mitch] Alright, this is home.
Pile out, pile out, come on.
- Looks like one of those
- Line up here
against the car.
- clown cars.
It is a clown car.
- [Mitch] Come hurry up,
hurry up, get a move on.
- They just keep piling out.
- Lou Gossett Junior
- I will read to you
from the penal code.
- will be out here to chat
with you a little later.
- Article four.
Employment at Road Camps.
- Ah, the original cast
of the dirty dozen.
- In your case, cotton pickin',
is not to exceed $2.50
a day for each day.
Of course it's only right
you should pay for
- And that's before
taxes.
- your room and board.
So the code goes on to say,
"The net credits to
each convict's account
"shall not be permitted
to exceed 75 cents a day."
That's your take home pay.
However, it may console you
- Cubby!
- to know that you're
doing a noble thing here.
- Gregor.
- Helping gettin' one
of your country's vital crops.
Now, in addition
to paying for your
- Annette!
- room and medical expenses
and so on, you also
- Hoppy!
- have to pay and I quote,
"Pro-rate the cost
- Mabel.
- "of reward for
capturin' escapees
"from the camp."
- Mabel.
- "Which reward is hereby fixed
"at sum of $200."
- And, Mabel.
- Now that means if any
of you monkeys escapes,
enough dough will be taken
from the daily pay of the
rest of ya,
- Monkey dough?
- to make up a kitty
of $200 for the reward.
- [Joel] And if you land on
free parking you get it back,
which is great.
- Just figure you're
on an honor farm.
- [Tom] You can grow
honor like that?
- Well, some more crows to
follow the big red machine.
- [Tom] What the
hell does that mean?
Looks like his hat is
welded to his head.
- What do you have to
call us convicts for,
mister?
- You pick 400 pounds a day,
and I'll call you
cotton pickers.
- [Joel] Say, I like that.
- [Tom] Hey you,
quit hoppin' around.
- How old are you baby?
- 19.
How did you know
to call me that?
- Why?
- 'Cause of the feet
in your pajamas.
- That's what
everybody calls me.
Baby.
(chuckles)
- I should think so.
- [Tom] You'll be perfect
for my experiments.
- Friends, huh?
- Hmm, bookends.
- We're sisters.
- Oh, wow.
- How did they
tangle with the law?
- Hitchhiking, vags.
- We're not vagrants.
We're on our way to
LA for a booking.
- We're entertainers.
- Oh yeah, I bet.
- Singers.
- Well, that's what
this place needs.
Entertainment.
- [Joel] I myself dabble in
ventriloquism.
- After the cotton's
picked and ginned.
- [Tom] Will you stop
bouncing around back there?
- Get these people squared away.
Show them where to sleep and
sell them some work clothes.
- Alright kids, follow me.
(slow doo-wop music)
- [Tom] Killer sax, man.
- Just kids.
- Yeah, but what kids.
(chuckles)
Well, here's to cotton pickin',
and little gal cotton pickers.
- Shut up.
- Uh let's see at $20
bucks a head that's
$140 you owe me.
- I know, I know.
- [Crow] I have that
much in my skin.
- This goes right
into a new TV set
for the wife.
- He should put it
in a bank.
- Anniversary present.
(chuckles)
- Osh Posh, come with daddy.
- Thank you.
("Love Theme Instrumental")
- [Russ] Jackson!
- Yes, sir?
- Hey, little man.
Come here.
- Come here.
- [Tom] Huh?
- What were you
doing in the house?
- I was just bringing in
today's tallies, Mr. Tropp.
- You look real
pretty in lipstick.
- Works every time.
- What do you mean?
There's no lipstick.
- Go draw your time.
You've got 15 minutes to
get off of this place.
- But Mr. Tropp--
- Get your pay and get lost!
(exhales)
- Am I the sultriest
person you've
ever seen in your
whole, entire life?
Oops.
(music shuts off)
(vacuum whirs)
- [Tom] Fred, I'm home.
Oh, it's you.
(vacuum shuts off)
- Hi, Russ.
- You missed a spot.
- What's the matter honey?
I'm not finished yet.
- Yes, you are finished.
You just washed yourself
out of a housekeeper's job.
- Why Russ, what
in the world is--
- I warned you about
chintzin' around.
I warned you about
that guy Jackson.
I told you that that
was the last time
I was gonna warn ya.
Now get your
clothes and get out.
- [Tom] But I'm wearing my
clothes.
- Go back to picking cotton.
- Oh no Russ, please.
I'm sorry, honey, I
promise you I'll be good.
Please Russ, I've
worked hard for you.
I've done everything I could to
make you happy.
- Say, she is
friendly
- And another thing.
Don't do any talking.
Or bragging.
You'll spend the
rest of your time
in the county clink.
- Hogan!
- I hate tramps.
Male or female.
Now, get outta here.
♪ Get to feeling like
a rolling stone ♪
♪ Haven't got a place to ♪
♪ call my own ♪
- What are those?
♪ I keep playing
enough with nothin' ♪
♪ And the time has flown ♪
♪ Rollin' ♪
♪ Like a rollin' stone ♪
♪ Want to know that ♪
♪ When I turn ♪
- That guitar makes
♪ The key ♪
amazing sounds.
♪ There is some-- ♪
- Hey, look,
it's Greg Brady!
- It's Greg Brady!
♪ Instead of losing
empty hours ♪
♪ And the tears I've known ♪
♪ Rollin' ♪
♪ Like a rollin' stone ♪
- [Joel] Smooth.
♪ Knockin' around ♪
- Check out the lever action.
♪ Town after town ♪
Nice fulcrum.
♪ Big towns and small ♪
♪ Towns ♪
- You can see a lot
of corns from here.
♪ They're all just towns ♪
You know, it really
makes me miss
the potato and cotton fields
of Earth.
♪ We're just rolling along ♪
♪ Gotta find a place ♪
- Hey, it's blonde
Lemon Jefferson.
♪ I wanna settle
down with someone ♪
♪ Never be alone ♪
- [Tom] Anyone want a sno-cone?
I can go to the galley.
♪ Instead of gettin' nowhere ♪
♪ Like a rollin' stone ♪
- Oh, no thanks.
♪ Get to feeling like a ♪
♪ rollin' stone ♪
Big ending.
♪ Haven't got a place
to call my own ♪
- Uh, well the show's
already started,
but I can seat you up front.
♪ And the time has flown ♪
♪ Oh, rollin' ♪
♪ Like a rollin'-- ♪
- [Joel] Ix-nay on the
ump-ay and rhyme-gay.
- Get outta here, you peeper!
- Tell him, Greg!
- What you got, I ain't
interested in seeing.
- [Tom] This is really gonna
make the reunion show hard.
Greg's back from
Sweden and he looks
way different.
- She just got out
of the hive.
- This is my bed.
- What do you mean?
This is where they put me.
- It was mine before.
- We're sisters,
and we're staying together.
- I don't care if
you're Siamese twins!
- Catfight.
- Keep your hands off her,
you big trollop.
- Trollop fight.
- What's that mean?
Trollop?
- Trollop my dear,
means a soiled dove.
A fallen angel.
To uh, put it sweet and neat,
a lady of easy virtue.
- Hey, it's Lenny and Squiggy
school.
(laughter)
- You take that back,
or take a beating.
- Take the beating!
- Okay come on,
if you want an Italian haircut.
(jazz music)
- Huh?
- [Tom] Extra mousse or
something, I don't know.
- Break her neck.
(groans) Break her neck!
- Greg buddy it's me, Tom.
- Break whose neck?
- Tom Servo.
- Who cares, anybody's.
Kill her!
- Hit her!
- Harder!
- [Girl] Scratch her eyes out.
- [Arkie] Harder,
scratch her eyes out!
- Come on, hit her!
- Hit her!
- Harder!
- Hit her, kick her!
- Kill her!
- Hit her!
- [Arkie] Harder and
harder, scratch her!
- Hit her!
- Hit her, kick her!
(screams)
(laughter)
- Ow, right in the eye hole.
- [Joel] Oh he's blind,
that's real funny.
Real good, Greg.
- Kill her!
- Come on!
- Go, yeah!
(women yelling)
- [Woman] Fight her, fight her!
- [Lady] Come on,
Janie, pull her hair!
- [Arkie] Come on, kill her!
(women yelling)
- [Joel] Alright,
I'll break it up.
Oh. Sorry, excuse me.
- Who's the big winner?
I got winner.
Come on, I'm ready.
- Don't hit me in
the mouth again,
you'll break my dental plate.
- This what you
call entertainment?
- Well you missed the
big Cossack number.
- You take a different
bed or a broken plate,
now what do you say?
(breathes heavily)
- I say uncle.
- [Joel] Don't say it.
- [Tom] I say wow.
(chuckles)
- I advise you two to save
your energy for the fields.
You hurt?
(breathing heavy)
You?
- I don't know what
he expects from them,
they're untamed!
- Angelo, get the
rest of these people
onto the chow.
- [Angelo] Alright
kids, get dressed.
Everybody to chow.
(women murmuring)
- Now what was this
catfight all about?
- Don't call me a cat.
- Well you got a wild's temper,
- Meow.
- I'd say.
I asked a question.
- It was over my bed.
- It was not--
- Over your bed body.
(chuckles)
- Alright, that's
enough of this nonsense.
Remember what I
told you, Lillibet.
You're halfway back to
the pokey right now.
- [Joel] What about the Gumby?
- Cotton pickin' creep.
- Oh, save your energy.
He's all business.
- Yeah, all kinds.
Including shady, fishy,
funny.
- Dopey, Sneezy, Grumpy.
- And monkey business.
- I guess if we
- Did I get them all?
- wanna fight we will, huh?
- You missed a few,
but that's okay.
- Oh, no.
You're too tough for me.
Come on, let's go
to chow kid.
- Oh, we've gotta get out
of here now.
- Come on, Penny.
- Let's go eat
at the Mess Hall, huh?
Would you like that?
- Bleh.
- Wait a minute,
I gotta get dressed!
(doors slamming and whirring)
- Hey are you ready, you guys?
- Ready.
- Yep.
- Okay, today we'd like
to present our pageant,
Greg Brady, An American Legacy.
(humming)
- Greg Brady, the eldest
of Mike Brady's three boys
began his public
life at the age of 14
when his widower father
married widow Carol,
who was bringing up
three very lovely girls.
- He lived with his large family
in a very spacious,
split-level house
in a Los Angeles suburb.
He attended Warren G.
Harding high school,
where he was considered dreamy.
- Life wasn't all peaches
and cream for Greg Brady.
The pressures of a
huge step-family often
caused things to go wrong.
Sharing a bedroom with
two brothers would
cramp Greg's style.
He later proceeded
to move into the den
and made it very mod.
(hums)
- He wasn't ready
for the den life,
so he moved back to the
security of his brothers' room.
But again, he felt crowded
and he eventually settled
in the attic.
- The attic was good for Greg.
There, he blossomed into a man.
Nurturing his singing
career, just trying to forget
the troubles of growing up.
Like the time his hair
got turned orange.
- Or when Bobby left
his jumping frog
in the back of Greg's car
when he had a date.
Oh, the carnage.
Anyway, but that
was his past life.
Life was good now.
In 1971, Greg was
receiving 6,500 fan letters
a week.
That and his studies at
Harding high kept Greg busy.
(hums)
- Then in 1974, Greg was
faced with the biggest
shock of his life.
His family was canceled.
Without a primetime audience,
Greg's world began to crumble.
- There were attempts
to revive his family,
but none succeeded.
He had hit rock bottom.
Greg couldn't even get a
suite on The Love Boat.
- Brady lunchbox in hand,
Greg headed for New York.
Musical theater would
give him a last chance.
He appeared in the Broadway
production of Pippin,
but then disappeared.
(hums)
- It seemed America
had lost Greg Brady.
He was nowhere to be found.
Until...
Christmas, 1988.
- Greg was found at a
hospital in California.
It was him!
It was Doctor Greg Brady!
He had become a
doctor Greg Brady.
- He returned to his boy home--
boyhood home with
his entire family
and a Very Brady
Christmas was had by all.
Thank you.
What?
Go ahead.
- Greg Brady.
We on the Satellite
of Love salute you.
- You're one of the good ones.
- Thank you, Greg.
You are groovy. (hums)
("Love Theme Instrumental")
(motorcycle revving)
- [Tom] Good pageant.
- [Joel] Yeah.
I thought it was pretty good.
- [Tom] It should be
just on what I love.
- [Joel] Hey, it's Evel Knievel.
- Whatcha got Buster?
Telegram?
Alright.
- Mr. Tropp?
- Right.
- Bob Steele.
- Hm?
- Well, I'm Rod Iron.
- How are you, glad to meet you.
Your mother called me about you.
Say, you sure look like her.
- Thanks,
- She tells me you run
- I'm taking steroids.
- a harvester.
Haven't forgotten how?
- Nope, I can run one.
- Good, you're on the
payroll as of now.
Regular rate, and
glad to have you.
- Well thank you very much, sir.
- [Joel] Now I don't know
if you're into weird scenes
or not, but check
this thing out.
- I grew up here.
- How's the place look to you?
- Swell.
Gee, you really
have it fixed up.
- I really like your dirt.
- Looks great.
- Takes money, though.
The easiest part was getting
your mother to sell out to me.
- Yeah, I know.
- She does that a lot.
- After Pop died,
she got so she hated
it around here.
She wrote me in Formosa
she was gonna sell out.
- Landis!
(chugging)
- That's Gladys?
- Come down, I got a
job for ya.
- But I was just going
to the store.
- Come on.
Bob Steele, this is Jack Landis.
- Hi.
- Bob's gonna take
over your job.
I want you to handle the
field crew on Q ranch.
- I'll go get my gear.
- [Joel] Oh great,
first guy I meet
hates me.
- You can stay in the
Foreman's bunkhouse.
- Fine.
- Now there's cooking
facilities there
or you can eat with the
crew down at the Mess Hall.
- Okay.
- Landis.
Come here.
- [Joel] Salad oil?
- Get rid of that.
- I'll drink it.
- And Landis.
- [Tom] That's no way to pack
a reserve shoot.
- Guzzling on the job
again, you'll be off of
here in five minutes.
Go join your crew.
Okay, kid.
On your way.
(chugging)
- [Joel] Man, that
kids sure looks good
up on that combine.
Put some spurs on him,
make him sing show tunes.
He'll fit in real fine.
(dreamy music)
- Nature's rich bounty.
Corn, soy beans,
sore gums, spackum.
Mining, agriculture,
and untamed youth
forging an untamed land
eating their weight in cotton.
- [Tom] Men naked
from the waist up
watching Days of Our
Lives, day after day.
This is their story, the
valiant few who dared
to be different,
who dared to dream.
- [Joel] Monster cars
patrolling the highways
and byways.
- [Radio] But in spite
of this bumbered crop,
prices may continue to rise.
Why? Because of the
acute shortage of labor
in many parts of the Southwest.
- Hey, he's got a car payphone.
- Howdy, Mr. Tropp.
- [Russ] Hiya.
(imitates horn)
- I love that gag.
- Yancey.
Collingwood.
- Well, Mr. Tropp.
Looks like you're
gonna have your crops
picked clean and
baled in short order.
We just happen to notice
going by your field.
You got plenty of
hands workin' for you?
- That's right.
- Two per person.
- Picking cotton.
- Our crops are ready and ripe.
Soon they'll be rotten.
- I made you an offer.
- Rotten cotton.
- It's your move.
- You said you could get us
labor to pick our fields.
- That's right.
I take 60% of your
harvest, you get 40.
- Now, wait a minute, Mr. Tropp.
You said 50/50, you said--
- Now look fellas,
you took my time.
You've been talking to me
about this for two weeks.
- [Joel] That's the deal.
I get the labor, you push
me around in a wheelbarrow
dressed as one of
the Honeymooners.
Your choice, pal
- ...for you is better
than a dead loss.
- But I'll be needing
over 100 hands!
- 200 for me.
Where do you get 'em?
- Where will we get
- When I take a contract,
- the wheelbarrow?
- I fill it.
You need 300 pickers,
alright I'll get 'em.
That's my problem, but
that's not the question.
The thing is...
Do you take the deal?
- What can I do?
I don't like it,
but I'll take it.
- [Joel] Uh, sorry about
my friend back there.
He's kind of a hot head.
Let's find a way to
squeeze him out, huh?
(door slams)
(chugging)
- [Tom] It's Tears For Fears.
- Watch it there, will you boy?
- Or Indiana Bones.
- You're gettin' too much
trash in with the cotton.
We don't want leaves and stems.
- No, you just want
somethin' for nothin'.
- You askin' for a
belt in the Billy.
- [Joel] Why do
they look like the
Pet Shop Boys?
- So you're lookin'
for a workout, huh?
- Yeah, do you have
Nautilus or free weights?
- [Tom] Body by Bob Denver.
- In the baling shed.
- [Tom] Now there's a woman
outstanding in her field.
(fake laugh)
- Good one.
- I'll tell you something,
I'll never wear anything
made of cotton again.
Oh, we gotta get us some
jeans and some flat shoes.
- What with?
- We got credit.
Remember what the man said?
- 30 days of this and I'll...
- 28, starting tomorrow.
- Chihuahua.
There goes another fingernail.
- Yeah, now that you bit it off.
- [Joel] Come on guys,
we can help them.
- [Crow] Stupidest crook in
the world, he steals cotton.
♪ Oh you ain't gonna make a ♪
♪ Cotton picker outta me ♪
♪ Boom, boom, boom ♪
♪ No you ain't-a gonna ♪
- Shut up. ♪ make a ♪
♪ cotton picker outta me ♪
Don't even start.
♪ Boom, boom, boom ♪
- You know, the acoustics
in that cotton patch
♪ You can make-a me laugh ♪
are fantastic.
♪ Make-a me cry ♪
♪ Shake the stars ♪
- Well, they sure aren't
gonna make a singer out of him.
♪ But you ain't-a gonna make a ♪
♪ Cotton picker outta me ♪
♪ Boom, boom, boom ♪
- The popcorn's enormous
out there.
♪ Oh, you ain't-a gonna ♪
♪ Make a ♪
♪ Cotton picker outta me ♪
- Elvis has left the cotton
field.
♪ Boom, boom, boom ♪
♪ No, you ♪
♪ ain't-a gonna make a ♪
- Hey, get me.
I'm Santy Claus.
♪ Cotton picker outta me ♪
♪ Boom, boom, boom ♪
♪ You can make-a me sweat ♪
- Look at that.
♪ Make-a me steam ♪
Must get real lonely in
the fields, look at that.
- Hey look, way in the back.
It's Eli Whitney.
♪ Ain't-a gonna make a ♪
Just kidding.
♪ Cotton picker outta me ♪
♪ Boom, boom, boom ♪
- Fortunately,
♪ Ain't-a gonna make a ♪
he's got the guitar strings
embedded across his chest.
♪ Cotton picker outta me ♪
- Gilligan!
♪ Boom, boom, ♪
- Skipper!
♪ Boom ♪
- Mary-Ann, Ginger.
♪ No, you ain't-a ♪
- Which one of those two
have rhythm?
♪ Gonna make a ♪
I can't tell.
♪ Cotton picker outta me ♪
♪ Boom, ♪ ♪ Boom, boom ♪
- Hey, stop playing
your sternum!
♪ You can make-a me laugh ♪
♪ A make-a me cry ♪
♪ A make-a me roll,
roll, roll 'til I die ♪
(cheering)
- Strange alliances are made
in a hot cotton field.
♪ Boom, boom, boom ♪
♪ No, you ain't-a gonna make a ♪
♪ Cotton picker outta me ♪
- You know, there's girls
there. ♪ Boom, boom, boom ♪
♪ No, you ain't-a gonna make a ♪
- See?
♪ Mm, cotton picker outta me ♪
♪ Boom, boom, boom ♪
♪ You can make-a me poor, ♪
♪ A make-a me rich ♪
♪ A make-a me want
a seven-year itch ♪
(cheering)
♪ But you ain't ♪
♪ Gonna make a ♪
- Yipes.
♪ Cotton picker outta me ♪
- There's a lot of rhythm
in this scene.
♪ Boom, boom, boom ♪
♪ No, you ain't-a ♪
♪ Gonna make a ♪
Leaves room for no acting.
♪ Cotton picker outta me ♪
♪ Boom, boom, boom ♪
♪ No, you ain't-a gonna ♪
♪ Make a ♪
- This is sorta like
Up With People in prison.
♪ Cotton picker outta me ♪
♪ Boom, boom, boom ♪
♪ You can make-a sing ♪
♪ A make-a me dance ♪
♪ Make-a me rock
right outta my pants ♪
(cheering)
- Yipes!
You know interesting enough,
this scene was included
in the film
- Hey!
- Scared Straight.
- Hey, you cotton pickers!
Alright everybody,
back to work!
- What key is that in?
(groaning)
- [Joel] I like doing
that to the kids.
(grumbling and chuckling)
- Hey, it looks like
he's driving the swamp
from M*A*S*H.
(squeaking)
- What's the matter?
What's the matter?
- Oh.
I'm dizzy.
(sighs) It's so hot.
- Poppies made her sleep.
- What's the matter with her?
- Too much sun, she's too hot,
I gotta get her in the shade.
- She ate too much cotton.
- I'll go get some water.
- It's okay.
(sighs)
- Hey, nice field boots.
- [Tom] Look, field's
chock full of 'em.
Boys, too.
- What's the matter with her?
- She almost passed
out, too much sun.
Let's get her in the shade.
Open the door, eh?
Well, come on!
- [Tom] Mm-nmm.
- Here.
- Now roll the windows up.
- Here, take some.
- Oh wait, that's my
motorman's helper.
- Thanks, I'll be all right.
- Alright, alright, she
can stay here for awhile.
You better get back on the job.
- [Tom] And I'll start
pounding corn liquor.
- Afraid of the
boss, huh Landis?
- Huh, not at all.
- Unless he's doing
his spooky face.
- I think we better tell him.
She might need a doctor.
- I'll-I'll handle it.
I'm in charge of this crew.
- [Joel] I'm a barber.
- Now get back to work.
- They used to be doctors.
- [Tom] Well since no one
has any more lines here,
let's just uh,
wander off this way.
("Love Theme Instrumental")
(Judge Steele exclaims)
- [Joel] Hey, it's
The Donna Reed Show.
- Russ, darling.
Hon, you could have phoned.
- I thought I'd catch
you with another man.
- (laughs) Oh.
- Oh they left hours ago.
- Don't be ridiculous, Russ.
Though, if you don't start
coming around more often.
Sit down, dear.
- [Tom] Oh.
- Oh, no.
- Not there, the cat's
been sick.
- Bob show up?
- Oh, sure.
I put him right to work.
He handles that harvesting
like a real expert.
- Bob's a good kid.
- Yeah, he seems to be.
Do you think it was
smart sending him to me?
After all, there's
lots of other places
he could work.
- I want you two to get
to know each other better.
It'll make it easier
when we have to tell him.
- [Joel] That he's an android?
- Oh, Russ.
Why can't we bring
things out in the open?
- Alright!
- And ruin the whole setup?
Oh, Ceece, that's crazy!
Things might start to
get shaky as it is.
- What do you mean?
- Labor's so scarce this season.
The other ranches are
beginning to bellyache.
It's only natural when
they drive by my places
and see I've got crews at work.
- Well maybe it'd be only fair
to certify some
prisoners to them.
- Fair?
Fair?
I'm not interested
in what's fair.
- I'm only interested in
- Now, listen.
stuff that makes my
head look bigger.
- You know that I spent
$2,000 in the right places
- He looks like Dick Tracy.
- to get those county orders
changed so we could
- In another 20 years,
- get prisoners to working on
- he'll look like Boss Hogg.
- farms. And I chunked
in a big wad of dough
to get you elected, too.
Oh, no, this is my idea.
I thought of it, I made it legal
and I'm taking the
profits from it.
All of them!
- And you can't play
with my Tinker toys, either.
- Who else in the Valley's
got cotton pickers
at 75 cents a day?
Why, they'd die
- Jolly Green Giant does.
- if they knew that.
There's gonna be a lot of
cotton plowed outta this year
for lack of help to pick it,
but not on my places.
I'll have a monopoly.
Don't ya see, honey?
- Boardwalk, Park Place,
think of it.
- After this harvest,
I'll be rich.
- I'm using the shoe.
- And next season
I'll be wealthy.
- [Joel] Is he gonna sing now?
- You mean we'll be.
(chuckles)
- Course I meant we.
- [Tom] Well of
course, but you'll be
dead. (chuckles)
- Oh, Russ.
I wish we could just
skip a year right now.
- Yep, so do I.
(sniffs)
- You using Denorex, honey?
- Say, honey.
I just pulled a big one.
I'm harvesting for
Yancey and Collingwood.
I take 60% as my share.
They're good farmers and
they've got a fat crop.
- Oh good for you, Russ.
- That goes to fill your
fat little cheeks.
- You're really helping
them out.
Where in the world will
you get enough hands?
- Oh, I'll get 'em.
- Well I know where
two of them are right now.
- You know me.
I like obstacles.
- I know.
I put enough in your way.
(giggles)
- Yeah.
You sure played hard to get.
- Yeah, you let the
phone ring twice.
- I wasn't really.
- Gotta shove.
Bye-bye.
- Oh, please stay
for dinner, Russ.
- Oh, I'm sorry, I can't.
- Well.
At least a drink, then.
Your favorite, lover boy.
Gin and Tonic?
- Cotton Gin and Tonic.
- No, thanks.
(Tom laughs)
- Russ?
What is it that's so
important this time?
The way things are
going, I sometimes think
we should break up.
- Gee, you mean it grandma?
- Don't say that.
- What does uncle-dad
have to say about that?
- Don't ever say that.
Don't even think it.
- [Joel] At least not
until the crop's in.
- I may not show it or say it,
but I need you.
I need you.
- [Joel] Tooth inventory.
(sighs lightly)
- I'll stay for that drink.
We'll forget all about
business for a little while.
- [Tom] And just
think about genetics.
(sighs)
- Boy, I hate this.
- [Joel] Man, my eyebrows
look great over there
in the mirror, though.
(chugging)
- 57!
- Enough with the
bouncing, already!
- Hi there, Janie.
- Oh, hi.
- How's Baby doing today?
- Holding her own, I guess.
- But she's asked me
- What do you think's the
matter with her?
- to call her Squeaky, now.
- Gee, I don't know.
Some people just can't take
this kind of hard work.
- She was muttering
something about Ford
- Maybe she's got a bad heart.
- and dry-clicking a toy gun.
- Which your honorable
mom didn't bother
to have a doctor
check any of us.
- [Tom] He's gonna start
singing You Ain't Gonna Make
a Cotton Weigher Out of Me.
- 43.
- [Joel] Wait a minute,
this is a bag of rayon.
- Pretty good.
We'll make a cotton
picker outta you yet.
- Not on your
cotton pickin' life.
(chuckles)
- [Joel] Funny.
- [Tom] Wonder what she wanted.
- [Weigher] 40.
- Hey, who's the
guy in the cage?
- [Tom] Well, that's
my brother-cousin.
He likes sody pop.
- [Joel] Well, at least
the bag is cotton.
We can get something for that.
- We were supposed to read?
- Yeah.
Tally girl.
- I thought we
were sewing today. (chuckles)
- Because I speak Spanish.
- I wish I can get
a sitting down job.
- Why don't you call a
temp service?
- 10 pounds.
- Ooh!
- Igor, down!
- Igor!
- Why don't you warn a guy?
With two heads, you'd
still be a moron.
- [Tom] But he'd be
a two-headed moron.
(1950's rock music)
- Go, go!
Go, go, go, go!
- [Crow] Hiya, Fuji.
(chuckles)
(people chattering)
- [Woman] Go, go.
Yeah!
- [Joel] You know, prison
was never like this
when I was there.
- Huh?
(screams)
- Now anyone not behaving
spends a night in the box step.
(woman laughs)
- [Tom] We're going to a
party at the county jail.
- Yeah!
- [Woman] Go, go, go, go!
- [Joel] That's the
problem with today's youth.
This is how their
image of prison is.
(people chattering)
- [Woman] Oh, move to it!
Move to it!
Go!
- [Joel] Hey look at
me, I'm still stupid.
If anyone dances with
me, it's by accident.
- [Tom] Hey, we gotta eat
on that table. Get off!
- [Woman] Swing it!
- [Joel] Ooh.
Ask me about my
extra chromosome.
(chuckles)
- Hey, I got a girl,
I got a girl!
- [Joel] How'd she
find out I was a geek?
Oh, well.
(chuckles)
Whee.
- Jerry Lewis, geeky guy,
denture wearer.
(woman screams)
Whoops.
- [Crow] Hey everybody, get me.
I'm doing the Abe Lincoln.
- [Woman] Yeah!
Go, go, go!
Do it Janie, do it!
- [Tom] Gregory Peck,
this week on Solid Gold.
- [Joel] Yeah, I
planned it that way.
That's right, I knew that.
- [Tom] Wow, it's Vic Tayback!
(people cheering and clapping)
- Oh, Mel.
- What's going on?
(people exclaiming)
- Caught in the act.
- [Guy] Hey man, it's
my money in there.
- Just a short
intermission, men.
I need two dishwashers
in the galley.
I want two volunteers.
(crowd laughs)
Alright, alright,
I'll take you and you.
- I ain't no pearl diver.
- [Joel] Well that's
not a requirement
for washing dishes.
- Now hear me out, my friend.
I am a just man.
Even a philosopher of parts.
Possibly the most erudite
bum for miles around.
- An actor of sorts.
- But in this
day of crass materialism,
with dog eat dog
and man bite man,
- Come on, speed it up.
- I claim
that the laborer is
worthy of his hire,
and the artist of his do.
- I'll be a square to fare.
What kind of gum beating's that?
- Chihuahua.
- As majordomo of the kitchen,
and as Field Marshal
of the Mess Hall,
- And whistle master of
- I have the authority
- the Junior High
- To order you to
the scullery.
- baton squad.
- But I reiterate.
I am a just man.
And I claim that labor
is worth recompense.
Your pay will be pumpkin pie.
- A whole one?
- With whipped cream, man!
- You got it made.
- This way, boys.
- [Joel] If only beatniks had
just stuck with pumpkin pie.
- [Tom] Yeah.
Let's go.
- We should get out of here.
- Suckers.
- Intermission over!
- Every segment ends with
- Back to your African antics.
- food for some reason.
- [Crow] Yeah, you
know I'm hungry.
- [Joel] What was it
you were hungry for?
("Love Theme Instrumental")
- The other day,
I was helping Joel
with a very important project.
We were on the
Satellite of Love,
and boy if I wasn't there,
it really would have gone
badly.
(whirring)
Gypsy lies dormant, her
central nervous Simpack
temporarily shut down.
I'm helping Joel, who's
working tenaciously
with the skill and
cavalier quality
of a dermatologist
performing his 50th routine
face sanding. (grunts)
We were on the
Satellite of Love.
- [Tom] And there's a
line by adjusting the left
horizontal gyro and
synchronizing the output signal
with the feed input
signal on Cambot's digital
array motherboard.
- What are you doing?
- Um, what are we
doing again, Tom Servo?
- We're linking Gypsy's
cerebral data disk
to Cambot's visual
output device.
Take a look at what
she's thinking.
It's great.
- Can I help?
- No, last time you
helped on a project,
we had to jettison a whole
pan of burning rock candy
into deep space.
- Can I watch?
- Yeah, but just be careful
and don't touch anything.
- Okay.
- I think I got this
thing all figured out.
Let's hook it up,
see what happens.
- [Tom] Input 3B.
- Okay, got it.
Alright, it's all hooked up.
Let's see how she looks.
- Just turn on Gypsy's
higher brain functions
now.
- I'll do it!
I can do it.
- No, no, let me do it here.
I'll get it.
- Cambot, just roll back
to the entire contents
of Gypsy's brain and put
it on the main viewer.
- This won't take long.
- Shh.
- [Joel] Well, this
will be the first time
anyone has ever been
able to see what
a computer is actually thinking.
- [Tom] Well, there it is.
- What is it?
- Oh.
It's an 8 by 10 of
Richard Basehart
and some RAM chips.
- Oh, brother,
another great mystery
of the universe explained.
- Well, it could be worse.
- How?
- It could have
been uh, Bob Eubanks
she was dreaming about.
- True.
- Hey, everybody.
- Uh, hi.
- Hi, girl.
- How you doing?
- I had a dream.
- I know, you had a dream
and we were all in it, right?
- No, none of you were there.
- Oh, boy.
Oh, Cambot flash-forward
out of this turkey.
- We actually saw what
you were thinking, Gypsy.
(whirring)
- Hey Crow buddy come
on, what's wrong?
What are you doing?
- Oh, I'm sorry, I
was day-dreaming.
What did you say?
(buzzing)
- I was just--
we got movie sign!
(Crow screams)
(doors whirring and slamming)
(1950's rock music)
♪ Mmm ♪
- No big surprise in
♪ Never, never, never ♪
Gypsy, I guess.
♪ Lettin' him go ♪
- [Joel] Yeah.
♪ Dancin' at a party when ♪
♪ Joe walked in ♪
- Nice set. ♪ Came with Pete ♪
- Yeah, nice radio, too.
♪ But I left with him ♪
♪ Oobala baby, he's my Joe ♪
- Oh, you.
♪ Oobala baby, love him so ♪
- [Joel] Hey, I didn't
know she could sing.
♪ Never, never, ♪
- I still don't know
she can sing.
♪ Never let me go ♪
♪ Young 15-a ♪
♪ Love my Joe ♪
♪ Sweet 16-a ♪
- Nice percussion section.
♪ Let him know ♪
♪ 17-A ♪
- Listen to that high hat.
♪ Got the clue ♪
♪ Now at 18, ooh ♪
♪ Ah, oobala baby ♪
♪ Here's my joe ♪
♪ Oobala baby ♪
♪ Love him so ♪
♪ Never, never,
never let me go ♪
♪ He's got charm ♪
♪ He's got class ♪
♪ And all the women
love him, oh ♪
♪ Yes, yes, yes ♪
♪ Oobala baby ♪
(cheering)
♪ He's my Joe ♪
♪ Oobala baby ♪
♪ Love him so ♪
- It's a puppet show.
♪ Oobala baby ♪
- Thank you.
♪ Never, never, never ♪
♪ Let me go ♪
♪ I love to love but ♪
♪ Just with Joe ♪
♪ When I'm with
him, we go, go, go ♪
♪ Oobala baby ♪
♪ He's my Joe ♪
- Wow, how many dishes
did they have to do?
♪ Love him so ♪
A fork each?
♪ Oobala, baby ♪
♪ Never, never, never ♪
♪ Let me go ♪
- They're fast.
♪ Oobala baby ♪
- Oobala baby.
- He's my Joe.
♪ Oobala, baby ♪
- Oobala, baby.
♪ Never, never,
never let me go ♪
♪ Oobala baby ♪
- Oobala, baby.
♪ He's my Joe ♪
- Oobala, oops.
♪ Oobala, baby ♪
- Oobala, baby.
♪ Love him so ♪
♪ Oobala, baby ♪
- Oobala, baby.
♪ Never, never,
never let me go ♪
(crowd cheers and applauds)
- 16 weeks on Star Search.
- [Tom] They call it coffee,
'cause she grinds so fine.
- Hey, blondie, come here.
You have more than a
modicum of talent, my dear.
- Oh, you mean these?
- Thank you.
Thanks very large.
- You know it's a shame
you started heisting banks
at such a tender age that
got you in this predicament.
But I feel it is the
duty of we who are older
to help the talented young.
You know, this gift of yours
should be brought to
the attention of someone
who can help you.
- [Joel] Heff?
- To it, Mr. Tropp.
You know my dear in this area,
there are many homes
equipped with a large,
electronic box.
- It's called a refrigerator,
- With a window in it.
- but that has nothing to
do with my story.
- And in this window
appear pictures
that so fascinate the
citizen, that they sit
in front of it for hours.
- Well, pick me up
- Boy...
- off the bricks.
- Somebody's gotta take that
- The cat means TV.
guy outta the rain, huh?
- Very perspicacious.
- Um...
What does this Mr. Tropp
have to do with it?
- Mr. Tropp my dear,
has a not inconsiderable
financial interest
in a Cahoola city's--
- Cahoola city?
- You know, a promise
is a vacuous thing
unless brought to a point.
I'll consult Mr.
Tropp on the intercom.
- Come on with me.
- If he knows all this,
why is he still a cook?
(mumbles)
- Little electronic
device called a phone.
- Pinky calling Mr. Tropp.
Pinky calling Mr. Tropp.
Station chow calling
headquarters.
- Earth to cook.
- Alright Pinky, what is it?
- Mr. Tropp,
you may not be aware of it.
- [Tom] That phone doesn't look
like it was made
- But there's a girl
within our purview
- for a human head.
- who sings like an angel.
- Especially not his head.
- And looks like one, too.
- We haven't decided if
that's human or not.
- [Russ] Get to the verb, Pinky.
- Mr. Tropp, I'm
surprised at you.
Very surprised that
you didn't jump
at this opportunity.
I suggest after she pays
her debt to society,
that you give her a
tryout on your TV station.
- Look, I have nothing to do
with the programming, Pinky.
I don't know anything about it.
- Sir,
- That hasn't stopped you
from farming.
- the least you can do
is hear her sing.
- Look, I'm not
judge of singing.
- Sir, you're about to
hear her mellifluous tones
and see her beauty.
- [Tom] Plural.
- [Pinky] And you
would no more judge her
than you would a flower.
- Pretty articulate
- Who is she?
- for a slop cook.
- Wait a minute.,
Little blonde with a sister?
- [Pinky] Yeah.
- Oh, yeah.
Sure, I'll listen to her.
Send her up here to the house.
- Thank you, Mr. Tropp.
Thank you.
Now you go right
up to his house.
- Oh, thank you,
thank you, thank you.
- If you are happy,
that is my reward,
and good luck.
- [Tom] What a gut.
- What do you intend to do?
- Do?
Don't be square.
I'm going up there and singing
his ears out right now.
- Well wait a minute, kid.
Let's-let's talk this over.
- Yeah, think about it.
He'll probably give
you that corny pass
about becoming his housekeeper.
- [Tom] The one you
chomped on like a bass?
- Yeah.
Right out of the cot and
into a bed of thorns.
- Are you crazy?
- No.
I've got ambition, that's all.
- Is that what you call it?
- Goodbye, Janie.
(people chattering)
- You're not going up
there to his house!
- I certainly am!
- But you heard
what Lillibet said.
- Sour grapes.
She got tossed out of the nest.
- Oh, and-and what are you?
The next candidate?
- Don't be dirty-minded.
- [Tom] Well it's hard to,
Mamie.
- Pinky got me this chance.
- [Tom] Real hard.
- And I don't think
Mr. Tropp's that kind.
- Oh, wow.
- I can take care of myself.
- Oh yes, you can
take care of yourself.
- Never take help from
- Like a kitten can
scare off a pack
- a guy named Pinky.
- of hounds.
- [Joel] That's
your first mistake.
- Oh, Penny kid.
(stomps foot)
- Stop calling me kid!
I'm older than you and besides--
- Yeah?
In one way, you were
born before I was.
- [Tom] And?
- Listen Penny,
don't be a sucker.
The only way to get a
booking is-is through
an agent or a producer
or somebody like that.
- Yeah, dream on.
- Don't get this way.
Look.
We serve out our 30 days,
and then we go on to
Hollywood like we planned.
- You listen.
Will you stop trying to
keep my under an umbrella?
- [Crow] I'm my own umbrella.
I'm gonna be way out in
front of those people.
- You know I've
got what it takes,
and if Mr. Tropp can help
me to get things started,
so much the better.
You can trust me, Janie.
I'm not gonna make any nasty
bargains, no matter what.
- [Joel] Unless your name
comes up.
- When you've got ability,
you don't have to.
- Oh, I trust you.
Listen, you know that.
I trust your intentions,
but when a sharpy gets
to working on you,
you never see through him.
- [Tom] You mean those little
smoked fish?
- You think all men
are dear little cub scouts.
- Well that's what
you think I think.
You're not
interfering this time.
- [Joel] Hmm, I wonder
what she wanted.
(groans)
- It was that rat food
we had for chow, anyway.
- I betcha it had
a saddle on it once.
- Rat food.
- Life's a bowl of filth, man.
Look into the face of death.
It's the only way, baby!
- What are you now?
- Sorry.
(jazz music)
- [Joel] It's Napoleon!
- [Tom] I'll just put this
fifth under the seat here.
(chuckles)
I love that.
(cans clatter)
- Didn't get enough in
the chow line, eh Bob?
- [Tom] I've been
looking for these.
These are my mom's peaches.
(dog barking)
- You got something on you--
- You got uh,
something up there.
- Yeah, got it.
- [Bob] What's
the matter, Janie?
- I'm in prison.
- Do you happen to have a knife?
- [Bob] What for?
- I might have to
stick it in somebody.
- Oh now, that'd be a little
antisocial, wouldn't it?
- Not where I come from.
- It isn't funny.
- Penny went up
to the Boss' house
and she's still there.
And it doesn't take an hour
and a half to sing a song.
- Maybe it's Aida.
- Well.
Why don't you go up and get her?
- You know I can't.
Penny and I...
Oh, forget it.
I forgot you're
on the other side.
- What other side?
- The side of the
judge that sent us
up here.
- Sauron's
Dark Army?
- Who also happens
to be your mom.
- Okay.
Like you said, just forget it.
- Well...
Don't get me wrong.
Penny's okay, she's just,
well she's just a
sucker for a line.
- [Joel] Oh, really?
- Look.
Couldn't you maybe
go up there and-and
pretend to want
to see Mr. Tropp?
- Well...
Not very well, not
without some reason.
- You see, I'm a method actor.
- But I think I have one.
- Oh, good!
- On one condition.
- You push me around
in a wheelbarrow
dressed as a Spartan.
- That you don't go jumping
to any conclusions about
what side I'm on.
- It's a deal.
(slow guitar music)
Oh, thanks.
- Now you can't be
that naive Penny,
I just don't believe you.
After all, I didn't
send for you.
I didn't offer to hear you sing.
You came up here of
your own free will.
You promoted yourself
with Pinky to have him
call me.
- No!
- I just--
- He offered!
- I haven't finished.
Alright.
You came and I heard you.
And I promise to phone
our station manager
in the morning.
- I'm very grateful, Mr. Tropp.
- That's not enough Penny.
- There's still that
- There's one basic fact
- wheelbarrow thing.
- you've got to learn.
So learn right now,
life is a matter
of horse trading.
- There's whinnies and losers.
- Of deals,
of favors for favors.
(dog growling)
(knocking)
- Puff, Snowball, down.
Uh, those are my hormones.
- [Joel] That'll be
the pizza I ordered.
(piano jazz music)
- Um, sorry to
bother you so late,
Mr. Tropp--
- Yes, it's late.
- That's what I said.
- About time I let
the dogs roam.
You know, even though
you're a paid hand living
with a foreman, these
dogs wouldn't know that.
- Well what if we told them?
- Yeah.
Uh, Landis tell you about
that girl on his crew?
- What girl?
- [Bob] Well I don't
know her name, they just
call her Baby--
- Yeah, what about her?
- Well she almost passed
out in the fields,
she looks pretty sick. She
might have a bad heart,
I think you oughta--
- Yeah, yeah,
well I'll have her heart
replaced in the morning.
Good night.
- I'll just be out here
if you need me!
- [Joel] Where is that piano?
(dogs growling)
- Now, I
know you two love the
rich taste of field hands,
so here's a little
snacky-poo for ya.
- Alright.
Go!
(dogs barking)
(fast jazz music)
- Hey, save me a wing!
(screaming)
- [Joel] Good thing I left
my dog beater over here.
- Take 'em away!
Take 'em away!
- [Tom] Mamie, calm down.
Dogs can't climb ladders.
- Heel!
(snaps fingers)
- [Crow] Boy, to think she
- I'd get rid of that stick
- jumped up there.
- if I were you, the
dogs don't like it.
(stick clatters)
- Kind of dangerous
isn't it, Mr. Tropp?
Letting those dogs
run around loose?
Come on.
- You were trying to
run away, were you?
- That's a lie!
They chased me up there.
- Get to your quarters.
- I suppose they ate
your homework, too.
(sighs)
- [Joel] Uh, should I
get you a chin wax, sir?
- That guy was sneakin' around
down behind the kitchen,
checkin' the tin cans
to see what kinda food
you're feeding them.
What business is it of his?
- Maybe he's a nutritionist.
- Yeah.
(1950's rock music)
(people chattering)
- I'm playin', you know.
- Penny. What are you doing?
- Your sister says you're
really a sucker for a line.
- You look all shook.
- I got away from him.
- You mean you had to?
He doesn't waste
much time, does he?
- So he set the dogs on me.
- I'll kill him, so help me--
- No, wait a minute,
that won't do any good.
Nobody'll be able
to help you then.
- [Tom] Especially not him.
He'll be dead.
(chuckles)
She'll kill him.
(lightly grunts)
(people chattering and cheering)
- [Joel] Oh, wow.
You know, it's a lot
easier if you took
the guitar off at least once.
- [Tom] Hey you can't
dance, you're the band.
Get back here.
- How much?
- Nine bucks.
- [Joel] What are
you, Hans Brinker
all of a sudden?
- Three bucks
at any war surplus store.
- You want 'em or not?
- You go buy them there, then.
- Fat chance.
I gotta have 'em.
Charge it, Buster.
- Don't forget.
You don't leave the ranch
'til you're paid up.
Even if your time's up.
- And I thought Lincoln
got rid of slavery.
- Yeah, he's right over
there working on it.
Gettin' rid of slavery,
yeah, really groovy man.
I don't like you.
(people chattering)
- Alright, closing time.
Everybody out.
(groaning)
Come on, turn in.
- No dancing.
- [Tom] That's not the potty.
- Them boys is awful quiet.
- [Joel] Greg, don't do it!
- Ow!
- [Man] That'll teach ya,
don't mess with the lights.
- Hey, Greg's got
child-bearing hips.
- [Tom] Eek.
- [Joel] He's used
to living with boys.
- [Man] Chicken.
- Honey when I do a strip,
I get paid for it.
(chuckling)
- Oh Russ, you're wonderful.
- Thanks, Grandma.
- What about you?
Between this moon and you, I...
- Don't know which one
is which.
- I'm licked.
- Wear a necktie next time
so I'll know who's you.
- About Bob.
You know he's been
working a week now, and
well, a couple of things
that I've noticed.
He works hard.
He's good on that
harvester, too.
It's a tricky machine.
(lighter clicks shut)
And I like Bob.
- A lot.
- I knew you would.
Everybody does.
- But, look.
We both can't have
a hold in our heads.
- [Joel] That would
make us bowling balls.
- Honey, do we have to
talk about this now?
- Well, it's one of the reasons,
among other things, but,
look this has got to be settled.
- What you mean is, you
wanted to talk about Bob.
- [Tom] Well, I'm using
you to get to him.
- No, baby, course not.
I wanted to have some
time with you alone.
Believe me kitten, I'm
thinking about you.
But Bob's no kid, he's,
he's inquisitive,
he's been around.
Now, he's gonna
figure out our setup.
- Setup?
Don't use that term, Russ,
that's a gangster's term.
What we're doing is
absolutely legal.
- Alright, it's legal.
- Except for the parts
that aren't.
- No, we saw to that.
But your boy my dear,
is a do-gooder.
- [Tom] Don't be a don't be.
- If and when he
comprehends this setup, uh,
the situation I'm in,
he's liable to hate you.
Now I'm thinking of you, kitten.
He's your boy.
You asked me to put him
to work and I wouldn't
fire him for the world.
But I don't want him
to end up hating you.
- Kill him.
- No.
- [Joel] He's evil
and must be destroyed.
- I think you're right, Russ.
I think it would be
better if Bob were...
- Put to sleep?
- If he had other interests.
Oh, nothing matters but you.
And us.
Together.
- [Tom] All three of us.
- Oh, kiss me.
- [Joel] I can't go on this way,
my lunch is coming, ooh.
(machine whirring)
- Wow, some boys
just have bikes.
- [Tom] Reaper Man.
- [Joel] Watch modern technology
rip through this field
of teenage gals.
- Hi, Janie.
- [Tom] It's Reaper Madness.
- Hey, you just
harvested his sister.
- You look all beat.
- Not beets, cotton.
- It's hot, man.
- [Tom] You just fall off the
turnip truck or something?
- [Joel] I didn't mean for you
to drink it, you silly woman,
it's kerosene.
- Where's Penny?
- Funny, huh?
- Out there, working
at the head of the crew.
- Oh good, I thought maybe
that crocodile Tropp got her.
- Oh you don't seem worry
about him gettin' me.
- Oh, I don't have
to worry about you.
You can take care of yourself.
You little wildcat.
- [Joel] You little buffalo.
- Thanks, Bob.
You're real gone.
- Well, thanks.
I'm not expert, but I'm
- I like you a lot.
- pretty sure I'm still here.
- Yeah you're, you're
real gone yourself.
- They're both gone.
- What happened?
What happened to her?
- They're left.
- [Crow] Medic!
- [Joel] Combine
got another one.
- [Bob] Better get
this girl to a doctor.
- Are you bossin' this crew?
- No, you are, wino.
- Oh, the name's Dave.
- Hey.
- [Joel] Dave Wino.
- What are you doin'?
- I'm taking her to a doctor
in your truck.
- Not in any company
car, you ain't.
- Get back to your
Muscatel, creep.
- [Tom] Hey, it's Mogen David,
and don't call me creep.
You want a spritzer?
- [Joel] Stamp all
foreman, dead out.
- Well now everybody's gone.
(car speeding)
- [Joel] Oh, it's the
Purina test kitchens.
- [Tom] Well I,
pulled her teeth.
Is that what you wanted?
- I'm sorry, I have some
very bad news for you.
- I'm not a real doctor.
- Your wife--
- She's not my wife,
she works on the
same ranch I do.
- Oh.
Well the girl was
five months pregnant.
She died of a severe hemorrhage
after her miscarriage.
Must have started when you
were bringing her here.
- [Joel] Gee, I'm
sorry we even made fun
- Yeah, she was...
- of this movie.
- Lying in the truck moaning.
Five months pregnant.
Ah, the poor kid.
- Well, we did
everything we could.
We were just too late.
- [Tom] And we're
not real doctors.
- Do you mind giving
Ms. Duff the information
for the death certificate?
- Yeah.
I didn't even know her name.
Baby is all we ever called her.
She worked as a cotton
picker for Mr. Tropp
out in Welling Springs.
- [Joel] Hey, you got nothing
to explain to me, pal.
- Well, Mr. Tropp is pretty
well known, we'll get
in touch with him.
- Is there anything
else I can do?
- No.
We'll have to identify her.
- Get off my counter.
- And find out what
the family wants to do.
- Well.
Thank you, uh...
for everything you've done.
- [Tom] Or didn't do.
- [Crow] Wonder what he wanted?
("Love Theme Instrumental")
- [Joel] Meanwhile at
stately Wayne Manor.
- And she was five
months pregnant!
She was just a kid herself!
Baby, we called her.
Nobody even knew her name.
That's the worst about it, she,
she dies in a strange
place without friends
or anybody and nobody
even knows her name.
- Oh Bob, I feel terrible.
- She shoulda died at Cheers.
Then everyone woulda
known her name.
- If only I had known!
- Well why didn't you?
Why didn't somebody?
- Well Mr. Tropp is
supposed to see that
everyone has a medical
exam before they're
sent into the fields.
- No, no, it wasn't done.
- He does it himself.
- Well it was part
of the agreement.
- I-I mean our uh,
- It's the law.
- illegal contract.
- The law?
Mother, I don't
care about the law.
And I don't think
you will, either.
Not after I tell you
a few of the things
going on out at Mr. Tropp's
private little kingdom.
- [Tom] Wheelbarrows everywhere.
- Look, y-you're a judge.
- I'll be the judge of that.
- You got a job to do
on the bench, okay.
Suppose I came before you.
Do you think you'd
be doing me a favor
by sending me out to this ranch?
No, I go because I've got to.
I live in a shack, I
sleep on a canvas cot.
There are four wash
basins and two showers
for 20 guys.
- Which is great.
- And that healthy food
that I'm paying for.
You know what I found
out about that food?
Tropp's feeding canned dog food
and he calls it beef stew.
- Oh, no!
- Not canned, it should be
- No, Russ wouldn't do
anything like that.
- dry, that's part of
the agreement.
- What do you mean,
he wouldn't?
He's doing it.
Mother, I saw the empty cans.
I guess you didn't know
this was going on, did you?
- No, maybe Mr. Tropp doesn't.
- Oh, he knows every
move that's made.
- Well Bob, it's...
it's, uh, it's just that...
Russ is very ambitious.
- When did you start
- Well, sure.
- calling him Russ?
- Got a bunch of people
assigned to him on your orders.
They're helpless, he gets
them for six bits a day
and feeds them slop.
- [Joel] It's not slop.
It's science, diet, and it's
very expensive, young man.
- You take a decent young girl
like Janie Lowe.
She's no more a
vagrant than you are,
and she can tell you
a couple of things
that'd open your
eyes about how it is
to be under the thumb of
a guy like this Tropp.
- Bob.
(makes random noise)
I can't help myself.
- No, but you can stop
sentencing people to his ranch.
Look mother, don't
take my word for it.
Have the sheriff make an
investigation.
- Bob!
- Tell the editor
of the newspaper--
- Sing it from the mountaintops!
- What did you say?
You can't help yourself?
- I'm in love with Russ Tropp.
- [Tom] Mom, love's
a pretty big word.
- [Judge Steele]
He's my husband.
- [Tom] Oh, husband's
a pretty big word, too.
- You don't mean that.
- What did you say?
- [Judge Steele] We were
married four months ago.
- [Tom] Wait, so you're
my grandma,
- You never,
you never told me.
- my sister, my mom.
Did you marry Bill Wyman?
- I didn't know how to!
- You never told
anybody, I guess.
You don't even live together.
Mother,
that isn't like you.
You-you've never been sneaky.
(cries)
It must have been his idea,
so...
- You're learning.
Keep it up, mom.
- So people wouldn't find out.
Oh, mother I'm...
I'm so sorry for you.
- Don't be.
Please don't think
of me like that.
- But now I'm
starting to like you.
- It's hard now, Bob, but...
Things will work out all right.
- [Tom] Sure, just keep telling
yourself that.
- And Russ has lots
of good qualities.
- [Joel] Truth is
mom, you've been taken
for one long, hard ride.
- Sure he has, to you.
(sighs)
I just haven't been
able to find any.
- I was hoping you and
Russ would hit it off.
- [Tom] Well he
did punch me once.
(chuckles)
- Bob.
You said something when
you first came home
about wanting to
go up to Montana.
- [Joel] Oh, you mean
that thing about Montana?
- Maybe that would
be better, for now.
We'll, uh...
I'll pay your fare.
- They look like
an evolution chart.
- No.
No, thank you.
I'll pay my own way.
- [Tom] Oh, that would be fair.
- [Joel] Mom, could
you make me a sandwich?
- Good luck, mother.
- Oh man, I'm not
gettin' paid enough.
- Bob!
Bob!
- [Joel] Love me.
- Jim.
- I want you to...
- [Tom] Yeah?
Anything I can help you
- I want you to get me a
- with in here ma'am?
- Custody Order blank.
(sniffs)
I'm gonna send you on an errand.
- [Tom] Up to Mount Pilot?
- Yes, Judge Steele.
- Okay, I'll go
get my one bullet.
(cries)
- [Joel] Hey, Greg
Brady's leadin' the group.
- Yeah.
- What's the idea, taking
that girl off this place
without permission?
Where is she?
- I don't know,
something to do.
- She's dead.
(woman screams)
- [Joel] Well when can
she be back on the job?
- What do you expect
me to do, break up?
- She was gonna have a baby.
- I didn't know
she was pregnant.
- No, but you knew something
was wrong. I warned you.
The fields killed her, Mac.
- Hey, call me Big Mac.
- Your fields.
- That's just about
enough outta you, Buster.
- You're not kidding,
it's the last word.
I'm checkin' off the place.
- [Tom] No, that
was the last word.
- [Joel] Hiya, Greg.
- Hi, Janie.
- Hi, other girl.
- Hi.
- [Tom] They didn't caulk
that float very well.
- I heard what you said.
(machine starts up)
That's awful about Baby.
She-she didn't
even have a chance.
Why couldn't she had said
something to somebody?
- I don't know, Janie.
Maybe she was...
- Rock stupid.
- She was ashamed or...
- [Tom] Hey Joel, I
was kinda wondering.
What does real cotton feel like?
- Some people never seem
- Oh I can show
you what that is.
- to learn to stick up
for themselves.
- Hey, Gypsy,
come on into the theater.
- That guy Tropp.
- Gypsy?
- [Gypsy] Hello?
- In my book...
- Hey, Gypsy?
Okay, look up at the screen.
Remember when they
showed the cotton?
Use your teledine
vector to figure it out.
Will you reproduce
some cotton for us?
- Is it true what you told
(Gypsy groans) Mr. Tropp?
Are you really checking out?
- [Joel] Okay, uh...
- Oh, gross.
- Oh,
it's not done yet, Joel.
- [Joel] Uh Gypsy,
will you run up to the,
to the main ship
and make some new,
make a new batch for us?
- Alright, Joel.
- Just put it on
the main table there, yep.
(Gypsy mumbles)
- [Bob] After you
get outta here,
- It's like fluffy pudding.
- where are you gonna go?
- Probably back
home to Du Quoin.
- I'd like to see you again.
Lots of times.
- Oh, sure Bob.
- And then stop abruptly.
Breaking your heart
- That's what I want,
too.
- like a toy.
- But if you go, I...
- This stuff smells, Joel.
- I may never see you again.
(romantic music)
(Crow grunting)
- Tastes like Juicy Fruit
and pizza.
- I'm not worried about that.
You'll never get lost.
- As long as you have
a compass and a dream.
- But you know honey,
before you said about...
you being stuck here and I'm,
trying to run away.
Well, I'm not leaving.
I'm gonna stay.
- [Crow] And then
stay some more.
- Tropp will have to
throw me off the place.
I'm gonna stay
and I'm gonna look after you.
And I'm gonna take care
of that guy Tropp, too.
- [Joel] And then I'm gonna
replant the whole forest, Ben.
- See, he's greedy.
He's gonna spill himself.
And when he does, I'll nail him.
So help me I'll nail
him to the wall.
- Oh use drywall screws,
they're much better.
- Janie!
Last trailer's leaving,
- Oh, we better get
out of here.
- come on!
- Man look at that,
(people yelling)
that's some trailer.
- [Joel] I bet that cotton's
- Goodbye.
- finished too, up there.
(doors whirring and slamming)
Oh, Gypsy, honey, look at this.
You are sick, aren't you?
(Gypsy vomits)
Oh, my good, ow.
Aw honey, lay down.
- Hey Joel, this is great!
- Lay down, girl.
- This is great, Cowabunga!
- I feel like Rosemary
Clooney in White Christmas.
Havin' a little trouble
with that Gypsy unit, huh?
- Yeah, it's something with
her off switch, I think.
I can't get it to stop being
on. ♪ Oh, the weather ♪
♪ Outside is frightful ♪
- Hey, this is great!
♪ The weather outside,
I know a wiener man ♪
- Maybe you should have
her fabricate something
less messy, like
salt water taffy.
(Gypsy vomits)
- I don't think that--
Oh, that's just great, Tom.
- Yeah!
- That's just great, I've
got a sick robot on my hands
and all you do is give
me more stupid commands.
(laughs) To deal with.
- Oh we've got a mess,
maybe she should bring
up some paper towels!
(Gypsy vomits)
Oh, this is great.
Yeah!
- Tom that's it, get out.
- I'm just having some fun.
- Out!
- Can't take advantage
of a robot anymore?
- Would you get out of here?
- Stupid human.
- Get out!
- Hey Gypsy,
make another Tom Servo!
(Gypsy vomits)
- Leave me alone!
- Happy birthday!
Hey I feel like
Rosemary Clooney.
Joel,
Crow, how are ya?
- Got outta here.
- Hey, hey--
- I don't care
if you're second
generation Tom Servo,
get out!
- Did you notice there's
a commercial sign there?
I gotta go.
- Oh, that's great.
We got commercial sign.
("Love Theme Instrumental")
(people exclaiming)
I'm sorry Tom, but that
other Tom is gonna have
to be destroyed.
- Yes, ma'am.
- Well you didn't have to,
- What Bob
told you is true.
- I needed a friend.
You didn't have
to dismantle him.
- Crummy food, eesh.
- [Joel] Crow come on,
get out here.
- A cat wouldn't
eat it.
- Cut that out.
- And the beds, oh brother.
- Crow!
- And the showers.
- Sorry.
- All the conveniences.
Nice, cold, dribbling water.
But Bob didn't tell
you everything.
The rankest thing of all about
the boss and the girls.
- You mean Angelo?
- No, no, I mean the
boss, that Tropp.
Boy, is he rank.
- You know what you're
saying, young lady?
Do you?
- Did I stutter
- Are you telling me
- or something, Grandma?
- the truth, or
are you spreading
malicious gossip?
- Malicious truth.
- I can give you plenty
of proof.
- Proof of what?
- Ask my sister, Penny.
He got her up to his house
and was gonna get her
on TV and then he tried
to make a pass at her.
- But she fumbled
on the fourth down.
- Go on.
- Well then there was
more bad stuff.
- And ask Lillibet.
- Real bad.
- She was his housekeeper.
Living at the house with him.
It's one way of gettin'
out of pickin' cotton.
What a way.
(object slams)
- Got it!
- What--
- Damn roaches.
- What did I do?
What did I say?
- It's nothing that you did.
You come along with me.
(1905's rock music)
- Oh, wow.
Another musical number.
♪ You may think you're ♪
♪ Handsome, baby ♪
- They all sound the
same. ♪ You may think ♪
♪ You're smart ♪
♪ You may think you're so ♪
♪ Good lookin' ♪
- I think she's gonna insight
a riot.
♪ That you could steal ♪
♪ My heart ♪
- Hey, someone get
some animal tranquilizers.
♪ Baby, as a salamander ♪
♪ Slip and slide away ♪
♪ You're as tricky as a ♪
- Well maybe that dog food
is good for 'em.
She's really got a shiny coat.
- It's a Hi-Pro glow.
♪ Oh, wiggle ♪
♪ And jiggle and
wriggle and rock ♪
♪ Jiggle and wiggle
and wiggle and rock ♪
She's just reading
the stage directions.
♪ Slip and slide away ♪
- [Crow] Nice lighting.
♪ Oh, jiggle and wiggle
ad wriggle and rock ♪
♪ Jiggle and wiggle
and wriggle and rock ♪
and wiggle and rock ♪
♪ I don't want you today ♪
- [Tom] She's the one who caused
all that trouble at Attica.
(people cheering)
- [Joel] Yipes.
♪ You're so sure
you're my desire ♪
♪ But you should be told ♪
- I'm in love.
- Duck!
♪ With a blazin' fire ♪
- She's got a
really neat body.
♪ You wouldn't leave me cold ♪
♪ But you're as
slimy baby as a ♪
♪ Salamander ♪
♪ Slip and slide away ♪
- Why am I here, you guys?
♪ You're as tricky
as a salamander ♪
♪ I don't want you today ♪
- This just validated
my existence.
(chuckles)
- She uses more
peroxide in her hair
than an entire M*A*S*H unit.
♪ 'Mander, salamander ♪
♪ 'Mander, 'mander ♪
♪ Salamander ♪
♪ Slip and slide away ♪
Oh, thanks.
♪ 'Mander, 'mander, ♪
♪ Salamander ♪
♪ 'Mander, 'mander ♪
- [Tom] This is like the Las
Vegas prison camp I think.
♪ Salamander ♪
♪ I don't want you today ♪
- Las Vegan.
- Another example
of great lighting.
- [Tom] (scats) Baby,
pow, pow, pow.
(cheers and applause)
- Alright, that's
lunch everybody.
It's the deli tray.
Try and look smart,
okay let's...
I said look smart.
- Penny!
- Oh.
Excuse me, kids.
- [Man] Come on kids, let's go.
(swing music)
- [Joel] Another one.
- Where's Janie? I've been
looking all over for her.
- [Joel] Well we sold her
into slavery for some
- Angelo said a man
wanted to see her.
- Magic beans, why?
- Then she got in a car
with him and they drove off.
- They went off the ranch?
- Sure.
Out into the highway
and toward Cahoola City.
- Who was he?
- Well he had on
a suntan uniform.
- You mean he was naked?
- And he showed Angelo
a paper, and Angelo
let Janie go.
- Oh.
- Oh?
What?
- I think I know.
Come on, Penny.
♪ I know a wiener man ♪
♪ He owns a hot dog stand ♪
- [Crow] He--
- What do you intend
to do, Judge Steele?
- [Tom] And who are all
these guys on the floor?
- I'm gonna try
to clean up a mess
for which I'm
partly responsible.
- I'm sorry, I...
- [Joel] You're sorry?
I'm stuck being one cameraman
left and right in this shot.
- I asked you for the truth.
I think you gave it to me.
I just didn't think it
was going to be so...
hard to take.
- [Tom] I had no idea
this steering wheel
would be this--
- Hey, that guy's great.
♪ Boom, boom boom ♪
- Oh, it's Greg-Greg,
Greg Brady again, we like him.
♪ You can make-a me cry ♪
♪ Can shake the stars
right outta the sky ♪
♪ But you ain't-a ♪
♪ Gonna make-a ♪
One for Servo.
♪ Cotton picker outta me ♪
- She's doing a cover
of that other guy's song.
- [Tom] You think I look good?
I do.
- [Crow] Yeah, you could
make a good whiskey
decanter.
- They're coming in
on the field road.
- Good.
- It's 'cause of my BVDs.
- 9:30.
Get those people turned in.
- [Tom] Fluffy, Crouch, bad.
(Arkie singing)
Here comes Sheriff Taylor.
- It's a Sheriff's car.
- How can you tell?
- The car that they took
Janie away in, was it marked?
- I don't think so.
I don't remember.
♪ Cotton picker outta me ♪
♪ Boom, boom, boom ♪
- I'm gonna check into this.
- [Angelo] Alright, everybody.
Turn in.
(groaning)
- You better go turn in.
- No.
- Turn into what?
- Not until I find out
(chuckles)
what's happened to Janie.
(people chattering)
(kissing)
- [Crow] Okay, so tell me
something and be honest.
Do I really look like
Colonel Tom Parker?
(suspenseful music)
(kissing)
- Wait here, Penny.
- [Joel] Filmed in
America's tractor pavilion,
scenic Shawano, Wisconsin.
- [Tom] That's a
really tall tractor.
- [Joel] Quick.
Hop behind the manure spreader.
That's it.
(sniffs)
Yuck.
- [Russ] That's the man?
- [Mitch] Yeah, but he
only speaks Spanish.
- [Russ] Ah, so much the better.
- I'm so sorry,
- This is Mr. Tropp,
Mr. Morales.
- he's from Barcelona.
(Mr. Morales speaking
in foreign language)
- [Joel] Who's the greaser
behind the manure spreader?
Looks like James Dean.
- [Tom] Looks more like Jimmy
Dean. Rebel Without a Sausage.
(light guitar music)
- Go get Margarita and hurry.
- Frozen or on the rocks?
("Love Theme Instrumental")
- Penny you stay here and
warn us if anyone comes.
Come on, Margarita.
- [Joel] I love that man.
(Mr. Morales speaking
in foreign language)
- What is he saying?
- He mumbled something about
- "300 farm workers."
- shooting the kid
behind the tractor.
- "It is hard,"
- I couldn't make out
the rest.
- "so many men.
"But, yes."
- Some, uh...
(Russ speaks in
foreign language)
- [Joel] It's a fajita recipe.
- [Tom] Sizzle, sizzle, sizzle.
(Russ speaks in
foreign language)
- Migration permits.
To work.
- [Crow] Okay, good.
Now let's move onto the
chapter on making friends.
(Mr. Morales speaks
in foreign language)
- Okay.
(crickets chirping)
(object clatters)
- [Joel] Oh, sorry
about the garbage can.
(dog growls)
We'll just be going.
- [Tom] Posh, Puff, sic.
Really mess up the savages.
- Go, boys.
- [Joel] Let's get
out of here, Scooby!
(dogs barking)
(screaming)
- [Tom] Ooh, have you had your
teeth cleaned little fella?
Big tarter build-up there.
- [Joel] Oh, they're just
mad 'cause those humans
got to eat all the dog food.
- [Crow] Joan Collins.
Cut!
Okay, that's a wrap,
get the dog off.
Okay, nice scene everyone.
Let's get home, we've
got another scene
to do in the morning.
(grunts)
- [Joel] That wasn't
in the script.
- [Crow] It is now.
(grunts)
- They're really embellishing
- Hold it!
- here, aren't they?
- That's enough.
(Mr. Morales speaks
in foreign language)
- Si.
(Mr. Morales speaks
in foreign language)
- Si, (speaks in
foreign language)
- She's lying.
He's not a lover.
- He's a fighter.
- Come on.
Sit.
- Me or the dogs?
- They heard everything.
This kitty understands Spanish.
When you take Morales
over the border,
take these kids along with you,
and get rid of them down there.
- Oh no wait Russ, that's going
too far!
- You want us to
end up in the federal clink?
This is no time to argue.
- Mr. Maytag man.
- If you don't wanna do it,
get somebody else to.
You don't have to
get your hands dirty.
(dog growls)
You go along, too.
(people chattering loudly)
- [All] Humma, humma, humma,
rutabaga, (mumble)
Homina, homina, homina.
- [Russ] What's the
meaning of this?
- Eh, it's a big
production number.
- Go on back to
the bunk house.
Get them in the car, I'll
handle these monkeys.
- [Tom] Looks like
there could be a rumble.
- [Russ] This is
a mutiny, a riot.
Now go on back to your quarters.
Or you'll find
yourself back to jail.
- We'll take the jail.
- You set your dogs on two
of our people, Mr. Tropp.
We don't like that.
Look boss, I like hounds
as well as anybody.
But those dogs are killers.
- [Joel] You know if
I wasn't sure Greg
Brady was a guy, I'd uh...
- You value 'em?
- Don't keep comin'.
- Snap out of it.
- [Russ] Drive through 'em.
Run 'em down!
- Oh great, finally a good job.
(engine revving)
(dramatic music)
- [Tom] The cast from
a Tobe Hooper film.
(yells)
- [Tom] Oh, little punk
hit me with a Nerf ball.
- Come on, Officer Krupke.
- Alright.
You want a riot,
I'll give you a riot!
(gunshots)
(dog growls)
- Grr.
- [Mitch] Break it up!
Get to bed before
somebody gets killed!
- That'll be enough
of that, Mitch Bowers!
Put down that gun.
- What do you want, Aunt B?
- [Crow] And so, Manuel Noriega
quickly seizes the opportunity
to make his escape.
(tires squeal)
(car crashes)
- [Joel] That oughta hold him.
- [Tom] Right in the nunzio.
(people chattering)
- [Joel] Hold 'em, hold 'em!
Grab 'em!
Keep holding 'em.
Give him a wedgie.
Yeah.
- I certainly am glad
you're here, Judge Steele.
There's been a mutiny, a riot.
Now as you can see--
- Shut up.
- Oh, poo.
- What's this all about, Bob?
- This guy's a coyote.
He's bringing 300 wetbacks
from over the border
on Tropp's orders.
- Get some towels.
- He's already got
the phony permits
for them on him.
- Huh, Ceceel. Look as you
can see, there's been a riot--
- Search him, Mitch.
(crowd shouts in agreement)
- Maybe I wanna search him.
- If you don't, we will.
- Yeah, man.
(papers rustle)
- Wait a minute.
These are stills from
Yards of Leather.
- Take them into custody.
(crowd shouts in agreement)
Do your duty!
- [Tom] To God and your country,
obey the law of the pack.
(handcuffs click)
- I've just learned
tonight of some
of the conditions you've
been living under.
- [Tom] I read your contract.
I can't believe you're
- If you have an obligation
to pay to the county,
- working for this.
- so does the county
have an obligation to pay
to you as prisoners.
I'm gonna have you all
into court in the morning.
If it's the last
thing I do as a Judge,
it'll be to commute your
sentences to time served.
(crowd cheers)
- Then we're gonna do a show.
- And it will be the last
thing I do as a Judge.
- [Tom] 'Cause I just got a
reading for Murder, She Wrote.
- I think we might need
a few temporary deputies.
Bob.
- Find some for me.
- And you, and you,
and you.
- [Crow] And Scarecrow and
the rest of you.
- Raise your right hands.
- Man, oh man, this is wild.
(chuckles)
(crowd laughs)
Crazy.
(island type music)
- [Tom] This is
what deputies do?
Great.
- I think so.
Only they're usually parked
at a Mister Donut doing it.
- Hey, MTV.
Mexican Television.
(chuckles)
♪ Go ♪
♪ Go Calypso, go ♪
David Burns' new band.
♪ Sing the chorus ♪
♪ Everybody think
the calypso song ♪
♪ Comes from Trinidad ♪
- Mamie made it!
Auntie Mamie.
♪ That's all wrong ♪
♪ Trinidad's ♪
♪ Been had ♪
♪ We gonna tell you
that the calypso ♪
♪ No more come ♪
♪ From Jamaica ♪
♪ Hello boys, if I had
known you were coming ♪
♪ I'd-a baked a ♪
♪ Rum cake ♪
I can't believe I'm
♪ Go ♪
I'm putting up with this.
♪ Go, calypso, go ♪
♪ Go calypso, go ♪
♪ Everybody! ♪
♪ Go ♪
♪ Go calypso, go ♪
- [Joel] She's got neat
underwear in this one.
♪ Go calypso, go ♪
- Nice diapers.
They're Huggies, alright.
♪ Sing the chorus ♪
♪ Where come calypso ♪
♪ Trinidad ♪
♪ No, New York ♪
- This must be the theme song
of the Cousteau society.
♪ New York ♪
♪ Where all the
natives crazy mad ♪
♪ New York ♪
♪ Yes, New York ♪
And so they leave the cave
of the giant barracuda.
♪ Rancho ♪
(chuckles)
♪ Everybody doin' ♪
♪ Ol' Matilda ♪
- As we so end the film,
we are reminded of
our tiny friends,
of Mamie Van Doren.
♪ Go, calypso, go ♪
How was that?
- Great.
- Close?
- Yeah. More Gregory Peck.
- I've been working on it.
♪ Everybody, go ♪
That was my Chinese
gangster impression.
♪ Go ♪
♪ Go calypso, go ♪
This is probably
the longest minute
in film history,
you realize that?
♪ The banana ♪
- [Tom] You don't even have to
look up her skirt, it's open.
♪ Okay gal, shake the banana ♪
♪ Come on boys, and
carry my bananas ♪
- [Joel] What in the world does
that mean?
♪ Calypso, go ♪
Carry my bananas?
- [Tom] I don't wanna know.
- It's a metaphor.
♪ Go ♪
♪ Everybody, go ♪
♪ Go calypso, go ♪
- Hey, lookit.
♪ Sing the chorus ♪
♪ Calypso gal, she pretty bare ♪
♪ Her neck de pearl,
on finger de ring ♪
♪ Want to know what ♪
♪ Else she wears ♪
- So that's what the
Tijuana brass is doing.
♪ Not a thing ♪
♪ Oh come on gal, say ♪
♪ Rancho ♪
♪ I don't dig Joe
'cause he don't go ♪
♪ Tell us gal, why you
shake the hips so ♪
♪ 'Cause I'm gonna rock ♪
- She looks so
Latin, too.
♪ The calypso ♪
♪ Go, calypso ♪
♪ Me talking funny ♪
- So do they. ♪ Go, calypso ♪
♪ I take de money ♪ ♪
Got to go, calypso ♪
♪ I get to jiggle ♪
♪ Better go, calypso ♪
♪ Everything wiggles ♪
- You wouldn't know
that to look at her.
♪ Papa go calypso ♪
♪ Mama go calypso ♪
♪ Baby go calypso ♪
♪ Everyone calypso ♪
- Everyone calypso.
♪ Go ♪ ♪ Go calypso go ♪
- I feel like
I'm in the Tiki room.
♪ Go calypso, go ♪
- I wish I were.
- [Joel] You've got
the profile for it.
♪ Calypso ♪
- [Crow] Thank you.
(audience applauds)
- Thank goodness--
- Hello, there!
- Well there she is, folks.
Penny Lowe.
- Your pants are on fire.
- That little lady
is going a long ways.
You know--
- Hey.
- My sentiments exactly.
- Do you think
you're gonna miss it?
Being up there with Penny, the
the applause and all?
- Oh, I'd miss you
much, much more.
- Than what?
- I'd rather be here.
- [Tom] Prison?
- [Joel] Well we're
both gone, you know.
- [Judge Steele] Bob.
The foreman wants
you at the Q ranch.
Something about one
of the machines.
- Okay.
- [Joel] And he wants to run you
over with them.
- Hey!
Can't I go with you?
- You'd better say that.
You know, you can't
start too early
if you're gonna be a cotton
pickin' rancher's wife.
(laughs)
- Hey, watch your
mouth, pal.
- Bye, kids.
(sentimental music)
- [Joel] I guess we
best be going too, huh?
- Yeah, let's be real gone.
- [Tom] Let's mosey.
Daddy-o.
- Go, go, go.
♪ The calypso, go ♪
♪ Go the calypso, ooh ♪
♪ Go the calypso, go ♪
(doors whirring and slamming)
(knocking)
- Come in.
- Hey Joel, I hope we're
not interrupting anything.
- Oh, not at all.
Can I get you some RAM
chips or something?
- Oh, no, just ate.
- Yeah, stuffed.
Couldn't eat another bite.
- Okay, well what
can I do you for?
- Well, we were down
in the galley playing
freeze tag and uh, we
started wondering about
that goofy mutant Charlie
Callas guy in the film.
- You know, that bespectacled
weenie that no one
would dance with?
What's the story on him?
- Right, right.
I think I know what you mean.
Cambot, can you put
up frame 2325 and uh,
I think it's somewhere
around there,
let's check it out.
- [Tom] Yeah, that's the guy.
Look at him.
Poor sap, probably has a family.
- Yeah so Joel, what's the point
of having this guy in the film?
What's his purpose?
- Well I thought you
might wanna know,
so I got us all
goofy hats to wear.
- Oh, alright.
- Everybody gets one
and you get this one,
and I got myself some glasses.
You guys can't
wear glasses 'cause
you don't really have
eyes to speak of,
and then the goofy hat is,
the goofy friend is the guy who
wears his hat sideways like this
and always gets killed first
in the haunted house, like
guys?
Guys?
Hey, this isn't funny anymore.
- Oh.
- Get it?
- So it's like,
guys?
Guys?
- Guys?
- Come on.
- Don't.
(screaming)
- Yeah, you got it.
- Cool.
- Hey Joel,
this is kinda fun.
- Yeah.
- Oh okay, so like
what else does he do?
What's his point though?
- Well the goofy guy
is around to irritate
the audience so they
build up a real lot
of resentment so nobody's
hurt when he gets offed.
- Oh!
- Yeah.
Now, let's end up with
the goofy dance, okay.
Alright, that's
that's pretty good.
Anyway, you're catching on.
- Anyway.
- I lost my hat.
- I thought it's almost
time for the experiment
to get done with, then I thought
maybe we could do
some letters, okay?
- Alright, let's see here.
- Good idea.
- Let's see.
This one is from Cheryl Watson
in Shreveport, Louisiana,
and she says, Cambot could
you put it up on the screen?
"To the man and the two
robots, I love your show.
"I came home one Saturday
night and tuned on
"the TV, turned on the TV.
"I had no idea what
I was watching,
"but it was hilarious.
"So I didn't care.
"Normally I watch Saturday
Night Live on Saturday
"but now I watch MST 3,000."
- Live from space, it's us!
- Right.
Anyway, we got one more here.
And Cambot, you
wanna put this one up
on the screen there?
Good.
Oh, this one is from
a woman named Dee.
Says, "Dear Joel,
Servo, and Crow,
"greetings guys.
"Joel, you are
one talented human
"and I'm glad you
decided to give Crow
"and Servo a free will."
Well, thanks for noticing.
"Crow, Servo, I love
you little bots.
"Keep on doing
those group parodies
"of those moldy,
oldie movies, okay?"
- [Tom] I love your
little bot, too.
- "Stroke of genius."
And that's from a
woman named Wee.
- Cool.
- Love, Wee.
- That's us, I think.
- Love Wee.
- I think it's us.
- Anyway, so Cambot,
why don't we put up
the information for
the Information Club
and Tom Servo, you
wanna give them
our address?
- That's right.
It's the MST 3,000
Information Club
PO Box 5325.
Hopkins, Minnesota, 55343.
Be the smartest
guy on your block.
- Have the biggest
brain on your block
by becoming a member of the
MST 3,000 Information Club.
Anyway, that's the end
of the experiment, sirs.
What do you think?
- Hmm?
- You know, I think
we should keep
the Mamie Van Doren
films to ourself.
- And I think you
should file this.
Until next time, double-stuf.
(boing)
(triumphant music)
(computer pings and whirs)